Contact

+92 3119993642 (Mobile) faizanbabar0311@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/faizan-babar-2682a8198 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Web Design

HTML

Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

Certifications

SEO for Social Media

On-Page and Technical SEO

SEO: Link Building

Technical SEO

IAB Digital Marketing and Media Foundations Certification

Faizan Babar

Web Designer and digital marketer/ Need help in Business to ehnace your visibality and sales trough Online Platform?SEO/Web Dev Peshawar

Summary

I work with businesses and non-profits to define their brand, build websites, solidify solid SEO practices, and create digital marketing collateral that performs well for them. I believe that websites are a company's number one marketing piece and the best salesperson they will ever employ.

If you aren't online, with a professional website, or your website hasn't been updated in years, you are missing out on leveraging your company's most valuable sales tool.

My approach to website design and online marketing comes in much well thought out steps. The development process involves strategic planning and implementation to pull your new website, social media profile, and online and email marketing plans together, and help you kick-start your online marketing efforts.

I have the education, skills, and experience in BOTH front-end (graphic design) and back-end (coding) development, a rarity in the industry, as well as everything else that comes along with marketing your business online.

Don't trust your important online marketing to just anyone. I have been branding businesses, both online and offline, for almost 6+ years.

Web Tech Skills: HTML5, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Bootstrap,

WordPress + more

Graphic Design Programs: Adobe Illustrator, InDesign & Photoshop

+ more

Digital Marketing Skills: SEO, SMM, Email Marketing, SEM + More

- → WordPress Installation, Troubleshooting & Maintenance

- WordPress and other CMS Platforms
- # E-commerce Website Development

- Content Creation and Blogging
- ♣ Personal Branding (for Entrepreneurs, Authors, Photographers, Speakers)
- ♣ Print Design (Brochures, Posters, Business Cards, etc.) and Printing Services

Marketing Expertise:

- # Brand or Business Reorganization
- # Get more Terrific, Leads, Sales & Followers.
- # Marketing Strategies (Content, Customer, SEO, Growth, Advertising)
- # Brand Goals (Organic Growth, High Reach and Engagement)
- # Niche Research (Audience, Keywords, Hashtags, Competitor)
- # Effective CTA and KPI Analysis.
- # Community Engagement (Stories, Comments, Replies, Messages)
- # Schedule Posts, Engaging Description, Captions, Graphics.
- # Industries (B2B, B2C, Healthcare, Music, Fashion, Real Estate E-commerce
- #- Audience behavior Analysis

Experience

Upwork

Web Designer

February 2018 - Present (4 years 6 months)

Providing web development and SEO services on Upwork

CreativeHubDigitalAgency

4 years 3 months

Founder

May 2018 - Present (4 years 3 months)

Pakistan

Search Engine Optimization Team Lead

May 2018 - December 2021 (3 years 8 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

Manage and execute the online activities across the eCommerce function.

Create and execute robust sales and online marketing plans.

Drive top-of-the-line online sales numbers.

Drive more traffic, conversions via all acquisition methodologies including SEO, PPC, email, affiliates, partnerships, etc.

Plan and execute all web, SEO/SEM, email, social media, and search marketing campaigns.

Design, build. maintain a social media presence.

Brainstorm, plan, execute new and creative growth strategies.

Self-employed

Professional Freelancer

January 2019 - Present (3 years 7 months)

Pakistan

PACIFIC BUSINESS SOLUTIONS LIMITED

Digital Media Manager

December 2019 - July 2022 (2 years 8 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

Developed and managed all digital marketing efforts across the system. Partnered with Marketing and other business units to define and maintain website process., SEO/SEM/PPC, social media initiatives, and Facebook marketing that helped to get conversions from the targeted audience.

- Executed marketing plan and strategies that boosted site traffic, search engine visibility.
- Responsible for web analytics setup, conversion analysis, and reporting to the management,
- Established workflows and implement processes across the enterprise.

- Managed product costings, market analysis, and Facebook campaigns.

Mydrinkbomb Search Engine Optimization Project Manager May 2021 - September 2021 (5 months)

United States

- Developed in-depth marketing strategies by examining Users' objectives.
- -Build New And Better SEO strategies for a better presence in SERP
- Created marketing plans by analyzing campaign results along with identifying expansion opportunities.
- Improved marketing quality results by studying, evaluating, & re-designing creative processes while implementing changes.

Ruthie Davis Search Engine Optimization Consultant March 2021 - August 2021 (6 months) United States

Keyword Analysis / Domain Research
On-Page SEO
Off-Page SEO
Traffic Monitoring

Product Development / Enhancement

I started Their SEO In March 2021, My Duties include Keyword research for inbound linking, for this, I have experience of using google adword keyword tool, and Ahrefs keyword tool, I got brand knowledge of products in different industries as it's the main part of any B2B business, except this my duties in Ruthie Davis are.

- To check the inquiries ratio of premium members and facilitate them.
- To give priority to our members who get low inquiries.
- To research keywords and optimization of products.
- · Genuine and Replica brand checking.
- Off-Page and On-Page Optimization, Link building on Keyword Basis.
- · Managing Facebook ads, Google ads.
- E-commerce Store Management
- Monitoring website traffic via Google Analytics.

Forbytes
Wordpress Developer
February 2020 - July 2021 (1 year 6 months)
Page 4 of 5

United States

have been working as a WordPress developer in Forbytes. I have designed different websites (E-commerce, Online Ticket Booking, Services, Portfolio, etc.) using WordPress.

I can:

- 1:Design responsive WordPress website with a customized theme
- 2:Removes bugs from already developed WordPress responsive sites
- 3:Redesign already developed WordPress sites
- 4:Develop and design SEO optimized WordPress Responsive sites with flexible engagement models
- 5:Integrate themes according to desired requirements
- 6:WordPress marketing (Woo-commerce and Multilingual) and security services
- 7:Speed Optimization of WordPress websites

CreativeHub Web Developer June 2019 - October 2020 (1 year 5 months)

Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan

Costco Wholesale Search Engine Optimization Executive August 2019 - February 2020 (7 months)

United States

- -Developing and executing digital marketing and brand strategies in line with current and future needs
- Designing, building, and maintaining a social media presence
- Contributing to marketing effectiveness by identifying short-term and longrange issues

Education

iqranationaluniversity

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Software Engineering · (2019 - February 2023)